[Music]
hello
crypto I have had a lot of people tell
me in the past that they wanted to pay
me in crypto and I had a wallet for a
while but I don't anymore and I got to
tell you I don't know what my belief is
on that
um people want to pay me in crypto
because they want to preserve their
identity and I totally get that
um but I I'm conflicted first of all
it's hard it's hard to do it I mean for
me if I were to ever do it it would be
you you I would immediately take the
money out and convert it to Dollars um
I'm not particularly a fan of crypto but
I do like the idea of being able to pay
anonymously like totally anonymously and
that that for the most part can only be
done with crypto um it is hard to use
crypto for paying anonymously it is
still pretty hard because you still have
to get the bits somewhere and being able
to get bits I mean sorry being able to
get uh Bitcoin or whatever uh in a in a
generic way is is is getting harder and
harder to do um so but I still think
about and then the other the other
consideration is is I can't always Trace
where the money's coming from and
there's a part of me honestly there's a
I mean it this is hard I'm I'm talking
about a dilemma that I have I've had
this for some time um I mean use of bit
of Bitcoin and crypto is is something
that I don't really the best part of it
is the whole Anonymous thing in my
opinion um it takes like 30 minutes to
pay for a pizza they told us we were
going to be able to pay for pizza in
Bitcoin total lie
um so as a system of payment I'm not a
fan of the technology I'm not a fan of
you know what it does to our environment
and all that stuff so you know part of
me is like well if I accept crypto
payments I'm kind of like being a
hypocrite because you know I don't you
know but I do like the idea of anonymity
and people being able to pay but but but
how much really do I like that right do
do if I want to be able to have people
be able to make Anonymous donations to
me um are there other ways to do that
besides besides crypto and and and I'm
just going to say it um it's not just
the fact that I'm like buying into the
idea that that I'm supporting crypto and
by the way if you if you are into the
crypto thing I am not judging you I am
not judging you you make your own
decisions I'm just telling you about my
personal
decisions um and and one of them one of
my best friends by the way gives regular
I can't say his name but you would know
him he gives regular Keynotes about
crypto um all over the all over the
planet he gets paid $4,000 for Keynotes
on crypto all over so I and he he and I
regularly he takes me got me really
drunk one Christmas I remember and we
he's he sends me uh gifts all the time
and we we talk and um I actually kind of
miss him he's he's you know moved on to
some other things um but so it's not
it's not that that anybody who's using
crypto is an enemy or somebody I don't
agree with or something it's more about
do I really want to promote that kind of
system and there's some parts of the
system that I really do want to promote
and one of those is anonymous payment I
do think that you should be able to make
Anonymous payment to a thing uh without
having to be tracked and I mean if the
rich people of the world can have
citizens united which in America means
that they don't have to say who they
paid uh uh uh um you know what political
party has or what you know donor has
given the money there's no traceability
because that's their constitutional
right to not have to give up who where
the money is coming from and and that's
a point of debate you know for politics
and and economics and stuff but but you
know you should be able you know I think
every human being has the right to be
able to pay
anonymously um for things that they
believe in because some of the things
that they believe in are going to be
questioned the other thing about that
too is the source of the money where the
money where they got their money you
know this is this is going to be a very
controversal statement but it's really
nobody else's business where you got the
money
and that is extremely controversial
because a lot of the Bitcoin I think
it's safe to say a lot of Bitcoin is
gained through you know bad means I
can't even guess how much there's no way
I could ever know that but you know you
have you say oh I'm not going to use
crypto because that money is all dirty
it all comes from hackers and stuff
that's not true you know God you want
dirty money
how about selling credit default swaps
in
2009 there's some dirty money right
there and that was all cash right so and
you know there was no tracing that where
that money came from where any given
dollar came from so I don't but it does
it some part of me is a little bit
conflicted like oh I don't you know I'm
gonna if somebody's going to dump a lot
of money me in crypto how do I know they
didn't just totally steal that from you
know in a Robin Hood sense from a bank
or something and now they gave all the
money to me you know
and I I have a feeling this this kind of
falls into the same category as people
who have run bot followers on my account
on Twitch and I don't know how many
hundreds or thousands of I'm guessing in
the hundreds but I have had people run
bot followers uh and I think that in the
hacker Community I think that they're
doing it to try to help me and I've
asked them I've asked them please don't
do that I don't need it you know I I
appreciate the the effort for it and
everything so
there's there's like separating the
intent and the support from where
they're getting their resources right so
so I have to tell you I actually paused
on the question about whether I want to
take crypto because I was like well God
how much crypto is going to be coming
from like you know illegally funded you
know arms deals or something like that
you know or God worse right I mean just
go you just look through the blockchain
just look through the blockchain there
there's all kinds of stuff in the
blockchain that's that's completely
x-rated horrible stuff horrible stuff
and that's permanently saved in the
Bitcoin blockchain you can't get away
from it um just like you know the
viruses and vir DNA and all of our in
all of our DNA you can't it's
impossible um so but but is that enough
for me to say I don't want to accept
crypto you know what I mean I know I'm
overthinking this but if you like look
at cash if somebody hands you a hundred
you know they throw a $100 bill and
you're busking on the street you're like
playing guitar for money and they throw
a $100 bill in your in your guitar case
you don't ask yourself is that $100
dirty so I think the conclusion for me
is that um that we want to be able to do
what we need to an anonymously and quite
frankly that means that I probably will
add back a crypto wallet um because I
still think people should be able to
choose what method and system they want
to use use um I don't think that that's
being hypocritical I mean you can make
the same argument for being a hypocrite
because you accept Bitcoin that means
you believe in the whole Bitcoin system
you could you could do the same thing by
saying you're accepting American dollars
right and therefore you believe in the
fiat currency system that's controlled
by and Associated to oil in the modern
socio economical system if you were
truly a good person you wouldn't accept
dollars because you're buying into the
idea that America is is allowed to be
you know the controller of the P
currency
and I mean you can make the same
argument of being a hypocrite by
accepting dollars that you would in
accepting crypto so um I think the
answer for me is going to be maximum
Choice letting people and this goes for
other things too people can donate to me
on they can they can support me on
GitHub they can donate they can do the
bits thing they can do um you know
there's a lot of other things that they
can do they could they can you know do
the patreon thing which I lost access to
that account so I got to figure that out
um um but but honestly we should allow I
think I think that I should probably
start allowing crypto donations um from
the people who are in in situations that
do not for whatever reason uh want to be
uh Anonymous and the question about
being anonymous is a big one I'll make a
whole video about that but ultimately
being anonymous is not evil there is a
lot of people who are evil you know
jerks uh who use anonymity to behind it
uh but there is a non insignificant
number of people who use anonymity for
the right reasons um journalists um you
know authors for years for years and
that's a separate video we'll do about
that so I am going to add a crypto
wallet I I've decided I'm going to go
ahead and add a crypto wallet I don't
know what service I'm going to use if
you I really don't like giving coinbase
my money but if you guys have an idea
for the best way to add a crypto wallet
um i' really I really appreciate your
feedback even in the comments or send me
message directly however you feel this
is actually another reason that I might
go back to IRC although Twitter already
sorry twitch already supports
IRC um and and it does right now there
is a requirement to have a phone number
associated and that's just to keep down
the trolls we've had a lot of bots and a
lot of trolls in there and um I
appreciate your feedback on that what
you might want to do there that's all